RG 002:025, Select Committee on Children
Connecticut State Library
Select Committee on Children records
1988-2000, bulk 1993-1994
1993-2000
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. General Assembly. Select Committee on Children
1.25 cubic feet
The Select Committee on Children was created in 1992 and began meeting in January 1993. Its purpose is to provide both greater focus and priority to such issues as child abuse, poverty, hunger, and adoption.
RG002_025_CHILD
1999-161
Historical Note
The Select Committee on Children was created in 1992 and began meeting in January 1993. Its purpose is to provide both greater focus and priority to such issues as child abuse, poverty, hunger, and adoption. During 1993 the Committee formed eleven interim pilot studies, each examining an issue for potential legislation. The pilot studies were: amount of children under 21 receiveing medicaid; child support; constitutional amendment on children's rights; developmental issues of preschool homeless children; emergency medical services for children; foster parents issues; high school volunteer program; playground safety; preventative measures for child abuse; services for medically at risk children; and Youth Advisory Board.
Scope and Content
The records contain agendas and minutes of Committee meetings as well as agendas, minutes, and research material of the interim pilot study groups. There are no documents from the high school volunteer program interim pilot study. The meeting documents present for 1995-2000 are scant.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Child abuse -- Connecticut -- Prevention; Child welfare -- Connecticut; Children -- Health and hygiene -- Connecticut; Children -- Services for -- Connecticut; Community health services for children -- Connecticut; Connecticut. General Assembly. Select Committee on Children -- Records and correspondence; Emergency medical services -- Connecticut; Foster parents -- Connecticut; Homeless children -- Connecticut; Pediatric emergency services -- Connecticut; Playgrounds -- Connecticut -- Safety measures
Document Types:
Agendas (administrative records); Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records); Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- 1993-1994
  - Agendas and minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bills, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Interim Pilot Studies
    - Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Amount of Children under 21 Currently Receiving Medicaid - agendas and minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Amount of Children under 21 Currently Receiving Medicaid - research material, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Child Support - agendas and minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Child Support - research material, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Constitutional Amerndment on Children's Rights - agendas and minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Constitutional Amendment on Children's Rights - research matieral, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Developmental Issues of Preschool Homeless Children - agendas and minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Developmental Issues of Preschool Homeless Children - research material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Emergency Medical Services for Children - agendas and minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Emergency Medical Services for Children - reserch material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Foster Parents Issues - agendas and minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Foster Parents Issues - research material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Playground Safety - agendas and minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Playground Safety - research material, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Preventative Measures for Child Abuse - agendas and minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Preventative Measures for Child Abuse - research material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19-23)
    - Services for Medically at Risk Children - agendas and minutes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Services for Medically at Risk Children - research material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Youth Advisory Board - agendas and minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- 1995-1997
  - Meeting documents, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 2000
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting documents, 2000 January - March (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Membership list, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)